GO TO BED EARLY OR THERE WILL BE HANKY-PANKY
（《不早睡的夜晚會做那檔子事》）
Mommy is having hanky-panky
媽媽在做那檔子事
Daddy is also having hanky-panky
爸爸也在做那檔子事
If you don't go to bed early
你如果不早點睡
Your flushed body will go
發燙的身體就會…
Hanky-panky
做那檔子事
Up we get.
我起來了
Crawling out from under the skirt of a hanky-panky girl once more
今晚我也是從 做那檔子事女孩的裙底登場
is me, Zucchi.
我是阿木
Let's begin with the usual segment.
我們就趕快進入那個單元吧
Presented by Ginza Joyaux Couture Maki!
贊助商為GINZA JOYAUX COUTURE MAKI！
If your BWH measurements are guessed correctly…
如果能正確猜中女生的三圍…
-Hanky-panky! -Oh.
-做那檔子事！ -啊
This won't do. I was watching mindlessly.
糟糕，我不小心放空跟著看了
Don't turn it off. I'm watching.
不准關哦，我在看
No. Watching this stupid show will make you stupid.
不行，看這種愚蠢的節目你會變笨的
-I'm out of the bath. -Junko!
-我洗好了 -純子！
Put on some clothes. You'll make Kiyoshi explode.
拜託你把衣服穿好 不然阿清會爆炸的
What?
什麼？
Your flushed body will go
發燙的身體就會…
-Hanky-panky! -I'm back!
-做那檔子事！ -我回來了！
Junko! What are you not wearing, you female gorilla?!
純子！看看你這是什麼樣子 你這母猩猩！
Mr. Ogawa!
小川老師！
Don't you go Maido Osawagase Shimasu on me.
當我是《驚動您了》裡面的
I'm not Eiji Bando, okay?
板東英二啊？
You better not have a hard-on.
你也不要給我亂硬一通
I don't!
我才沒有咧！
Get up, then.
那你就站起來看看啊
Stand up.
起立
See? You're all ding-a-ling, aren't you?
看吧，一點都不像話不是嗎？
You want fried udon?
你要吃炒烏龍麵嗎？
Absolutely.
我要吃
With a fried egg. Make it half fry.
還要配半熟荷包蛋
First, you need to tell Mom you're back.
你應該先去跟媽媽說你回來了
Why? How?
為什麼？你是怎麼做到的？
I've got no clue.
誰知道啊
Damn, I was so close to having hanky-panky.
真討厭，差一點點就能做那檔子事了
What?
什麼？
Nothing.
沒什麼啦
I'm back home.
我回家囉
Well, goodnight.
那麼，晚安了
Goodnight.
晚安
It made me think I still had you.
還有小川先生陪在我身邊
It encouraged me to keep going.
所以我才能加把勁努力
Thank you.
很感謝你
Where has he gone?
他到底去哪了？
I recorded 11 PM and the professional baseball news.
我有把“11PM”跟職棒新聞錄下來了
Oh, right.
哦，對了
I've got to return this to you.
得把這個還給你
I don't want it. You can have it.
我不要了，就送給老師吧
Are you sure?
你確定？
It's no fun when no one else has one.
反正周遭也沒人有，不好玩
Here you go.
做好囉
Nice.
我開動了
It's good.
真好吃
Anyway, why do I go to the future by bus but come back through the toilet?
話又說回來
You'll have to ask Inoue about that.
關於那些事你得問井上
Inoue?
井上？
That's my dad. He's an inventor.
是我爸爸，他是一位發明家
What's up with that undercut? You look like an idiot.
你那是什麼鬼削邊頭啊？ 完全顯露出你有多蠢
Excuse you, what are you doing?
住手，你幹嘛啦？
Did you two have hanky-panky already?
你們已經做那檔子事了嗎？
Not yet.
還沒啦
Not yet? You're totally planning to!
還沒？你這樣說不就是預定要做嗎？
Kiyoshi was turned off after seeing this.
阿清看了這個就軟掉了
Hey! Give me that!
喂！快把那個給我！
Hey, folks in the neighborhood,
各位鄰居！
the old pervert is back!
變態老頭歸來了喔！
It's not mine, okay? Give it back!
那不是我的啦！快還來！
I haven't even watched it yet!
我都還沒看過咧！
Stop right there, Junko!
站住，給我等一下，純子！
It's really feeling like Maido Osawagase Shimasu.
這還真的有點像是 《驚動您了》的劇情呢
PROF. MASAKAZU INOUE METROPOLIS INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY
（首都工業大學教授 理學博士，井上昌和）
My former wife sent me an email
我的前妻發訊息告訴我說
saying that Mr. Ogawa was here.
小川老師到這裡來了
Now, I'm working in the same workplace as he is.
他現在和我在同一個職場工作
You are?
跟你一起嗎？
With Mr. Ogawa? At a TV station?
你跟小川老師一起在電視台工作？
But he hasn't shown up since he left without his belongings two days ago.
但他在兩天前突然消失 連放在店裡的隨身物品都沒拿
I've been trying to call him, but…
雖然我們打了很多通電話給他…
What's your connection to Mr. Ogawa?
請問你跟小川先生是什麼關係？
He's my former teacher.
他是我的恩師
I was in the baseball club at Katsushika Ward Junior High School 6.
我曾是葛飾區立第六國中棒球社社員
Boys worldwide were inspired by Back to the Future
當時全世界的少年都受到 《回到未來》的大作影響
and dreamed of inventing a time machine.
於是都夢想著發明時光機
I was one of them.
而我也是其中一人
No adult took me seriously. Except…
當時沒有一個大人肯理會我，但是…
for Mr. Ogawa.
唯獨小川老師卻不一樣
I believe so.
我認為可以
Work hard, Inoue. You can do it.
加油啊，井上，你一定可以做到的
Right!
好的！
For 38 years, I worked hard to fulfill my promise to Mr. Ogawa.
我拼命努力了38年 就為了實現我跟小川老師的約定
Whenever I felt like giving up,
每當我想要放棄
I remembered his spanking with a bat.
就會想起當年 小川老師用球棒打我的屁股的情景
Sakae, give it all you've got.
紗加惠，你就狠狠地打吧
Okay.
好
-Here goes! -Do it!
-要打囉！ -來吧！
Here goes!
我要打了！
Do it!
放馬過來！
Masa, I can't do this.
阿昌，不行啦，我做不到
Sakae, this is absolutely not violence.
紗加惠，這絕對不是什麼暴力行為
Nor corporal punishment.
也不是體罰
As a Katsushika-born former baseball club member,
對來自葛飾的前棒球社社員來說
compliance means nothing to me.
才不管行為合不合乎規範
Now do it!
現在就打下去！
Okay!
好吧！
-Ouch! -I'm sorry!
-好痛！ -抱歉…
Again!
再來一次！
Right!
好！
-Again! -Right!
-再來一次！ -好！
Again!
-要打囉！ -來吧！
I bought a large Showa-era bus for cheap and put it to use.
我運用了一輛便宜買來的 昭和時代的大型公車
Doc's DeLorean had a digital display for time travel,
博士的德羅寧能夠藉由 操作次元轉移裝置的數位顯示器
letting you pick any destination in time.
前往任意想去的時代
But that's just movie fiction.
不過那是電影虛構的情節
With our current technology,
憑現今的技術能做到的是
we can only travel to and from predetermined times.
事先設定好要穿越的時間長短 並在此範圍往返而已
I set the time 38 years ago because I wanted to meet Mr. Ogawa,
我之所以會設定為38年前
-It's Mr. Ogawa. -What?
-小川老師打來了 -你說啥？
Hello?
喂？
It connected. Hey, Nagisa!
打通了，小渚！
Mr. Ogawa! It's been so long! This is Inoue.
小川老師！好久不見！我是井上
Huh? Who the hell are you? Let me speak with Nagisa.
誰啊？我才不認識你 把手機還給小渚啦！
He's the inventor of the time machine.
據說他是發明時光機的那個人喔
Oh, is that so? Why'd you do that for, huh?
是喔，這樣啊，看看你做了什麼好事
Mr. Ogawa, where are you right now?
老師，請問你現在在哪？
I'm on the baseball field in Showa 61.
我在昭和61年的棒球社球場
What?!
怎麼會？
Anyway, I'll have to take a break from my counselor job.
所以我暫時沒辦法做諮商師的工作了
I'll tell them so.
我會轉達給公司的
-By the way… -And…
-順便問一下… -還有啊…
You go first.
你先請…
Oh, yeah?
-可以嗎？ -可以
Akitsu,
秋津
keep my belongings safe for me. They're important.
幫我把私人物品收好 那些對我來說很重要
Got it.
了解
-One more thing… -By the way…
-然後啊… -想問一下…
Go ahead.
你先請…
You're annoying me.
你真是讓人煩躁！
If you have something to say, say it.
有什麼想說的就快說啊
Um, is my son doing well?
那個，我兒子過得還好嗎？
Your son?
你兒子？
Right, you're Kiyoshi's father, huh?
對了，所以你就是阿清的爸爸啊？
Hey, Kiyoshi!
喂，阿清！
Your dad wants to know how you're doing.
你爸問你過得好不好
I'm doing good, Dad.
我很好哦，爸爸
What's with that undercut, huh?
你那是什麼削邊頭啦？
Hey! Who did that to you?
喂！是誰把你弄成這樣的？
My arms are dead.
我的手臂舉不動了
-Coach! -Mr. Ogawa!
-教練！ -老師！
Go ahead.
你先請…
So annoying!
讓人煩躁！
The call dropped.
掛斷了
Why don't you go see him?
那換成你回到過去見他如何？
Yeah. Isn't that what the time machine is for?
好主意，這就是時光機的功用吧？
The thing is,
其實…
I can't.
我做不到
-Together, let us travel through time. -On the day of the trial run…
-讓我們一起去時空旅行吧 -就在值得紀念的試乘日
I welcomed NASA and government staff onto the time machine
我帶著美國太空總署 以及政府相關的人員坐上公車
and took the driver's seat.
-自己則坐上駕駛座 -我出發了
-Take care. -The door's closing.
-路上小心 -車門即將關閉
But my ears went "eeee."
不過耳朵突然嗡嗡作響
Yeah. "Eeee."
對，就是嗡嗡作響
My semicircular canals.
我的三半規管出現異常
You can't unclog your ears.
你不會平衡耳壓啊
No! Stop!
停下來…
I'm stopping the bus!
我要停車了！嗡嗡…
I had no choice but to switch to having the bus self-drive with an AI.
無計可施的我只能將系統模式 改由人工智慧自動駕駛
It's pathetic.
實在太沒出息了
I invented the time machine,
明明是我研發的時光機
and yet I can't board it.
自己竟無法坐
Is that why Sakae went in your stead?
所以紗加惠小姐才會代替你去？
She threatened to divorce me if I insisted she get on the bus.
雖然她威脅說 如果要逼她坐，就要跟我離婚
Feeling on edge myself,
因為我當時情緒很激動
I told her if she refused to board, I'd divorce her.
就撂下狠話對她說 若她說什麼都不坐的話就離婚
So it was divorce either way.
那她不管坐或不坐結果都是離婚耶
Kiyoshi chose to be with his mother.
阿清說想跟他媽媽待在一起
My wife is currently conducting research on gender and harassment during Showa.
內人正以社會學家的視角 調查昭和時代的性別及騷擾情事
And it seems my son…
至於我兒子…
got himself a girlfriend.
好像交到了女朋友
That's nice.
那真是太好了
Mom, I'm going to watch a movie, so give me some pocket money.
老媽，給我零用錢，我們要去看電影
What movie?
看什麼電影？
Back to the Future.
《回到未來》
Is this your friend?
他是你們的朋友？
He's Inoue from the baseball club.
他是棒球社的
It's Masakazu. Nice to meet you.
我是昌和，請多指教
What a surprise, right? He shares the same name as Dad.
你嚇了一跳吧？他跟爸爸同名同姓耶
Please.
給我吧
-Thanks. -Let's go. We'll be late for the movie.
-謝啦 -走吧，電影快開始了
I've seen this movie countless times.
這部電影我已經看很多次了
-How many times? -Wait.
-大概幾次？ -等一下
Like 18 times.
看過18次了
That's insane.
好誇張喔
-It's fun? -Yeah, it's super fun.
-有這麼好看嗎？ -是啊，超有趣
A time paradox?
時間悖論？
When you alter the past, it changes the future,
過去的歷史若遭塗改 未來也會因此改變
creating a time paradox.
那便是所謂的時間悖論
If you prevent Masumi Kuwata from meeting Maki,
舉例來說，如果阻止了 桑田真澄與真紀夫人相遇
Matt will no longer exist in this world. Something like that?
Matt就變成未曾在世上存在過 這麼說對嗎？
I can't say if that example is appropriate, but…
雖然一時之間我很難判斷 你舉的例是否恰當…
yes.
不過沒錯
What happens to Matt then? Will he disappear?
那麼Matt會怎麼樣？他會融化嗎？
When a time paradox occurs…
一旦發生時間悖論…
You feel a tingling.
你會有一陣霹靂啪啦的感覺
Not just a tingling.
與其說是霹靂啪啦
-It's more like a zap. -You're a university professor, right?
-應該更像是滋砰滋砰 -冒昧請教一下，你是大學教授吧？
Even if I were to explain, you wouldn't get it.
就算我詳細說明，你們也聽不懂嘛
Anyway, it must never happen.
總之絕對不能讓那種事發生
Enough! What time do you think it is?
吵死了！
Junko! I won tickets to Hanky-Panky!
純子！
For real?
真的假的？
YOU'VE BEEN SELECTED AS A PARTICIPANT
（挑戰者當選通知書）
What's this? A participant?
那是什麼東西？“挑戰者”？
I'm going to join Zucchi's Hanky-Panky show.
我們要上節目啦 就是阿木主持的《那檔子事》
It's the most extreme show right now.
是目前最激進的節目
Someone has a nip slip every week.
每週都會有人露點
Join!
那你務必要參加…
-Junko's not going to have a nip slip. -Don't get too excited.
-純子不會漏點的啦 -少在那邊得意忘形，阿清
What is it?
有事嗎？
But minors must be accompanied by their parents.
但是規定未成年人要有大人陪同
My folks can't make it.
我們兩個的爸媽都沒同意
Can't your dad come?
老師能不能來啊？
What? He can't. No way.
什麼？我老爸不行啦，討厭死了
He's annoying, stinky, dirty, and busy.
又煩又臭又髒，而且很忙
Say what?
你說了什麼嗎？
Junko's going to be on TV.
純子要上電視了
TV?
電視？
Not on this perverted show.
絕對不行，怎麼能上那種色節目
You've watched it?
你有看過嗎？
I have.
有啊
No! I can tell without watching it.
才沒有！不用看也知道！
No way. You're not joining.
總之不行，我不准你去
-Come on. -What are you doing here?
-你為什麼會在？ -怎麼這樣啦？
-Sorry?
-你怎麼會在這裡？ -什麼？
-Huh?
-你為何會在啊？ -什麼意思？
-Was it the toilet? -The toilet?
-是廁所嗎？ -廁所？
You too?
你也是來自廁所？
PREMIUM SATURDAY MR. NORITO YASHIMA
（《優質星期六》 八嶋智人先生）
Mr. Yashima is here.
八嶋先生來了
I'll make it on time. Yes.
在那之前會趕上的，是…
Right. I understand. Thank you.
好的，我明白了，再見
-Huh? -Mr. Kurita.
-什麼？ -栗田先生
We're shooting PS today, right?
今天是《優六》的錄影日吧？
That's why my phone won't stop ringing.
所以我的手機才會一直響不停啊
Oh, it's you. Check this out.
原來是渚，你先看過這個
Yes, hello?
喂？你好
Not out loud!
不要說出來啦！
Sorry?
你說什麼？
It seems our emcee has been tailed for over six months.
我們節目的主持人 好像從半年前就被狗仔盯上了
His only good point was that he seemed clean.
他唯一的優點就是清廉正直的形象
We kept him around for his scandal-free record.
當初就是看上他零醜聞才會一直用他
And we're about to celebrate the 300th episode next week!
下週還是第300集紀念特輯耶！
Where is he now?
他人在哪？
We told him to stay in his car for now.
總之已經告訴他千萬不要下車了
This is an article from Shukan Bunsun, set to be published on Monday.
這是將在下週一出刊的 《週刊文寸》報導
Preceding this, the digital version will be uploaded today at 4 p.m.
而電子版會在那之前上傳 時間是今天下午四點
Mr. Kurita is reaching out to people
栗田先生正積極動用各方人脈
to keep it from being published until the show concludes.
希望至少能拖到節目結束後再公開
Is it true, Tsutsumin?
內容屬實嗎？堤哥
If you're innocent, you could brush it off as a little slipup.
若你沒劈腿，坦承是出於疏忽才被拍 也許就能度過這難關
If you're innocent.
前提是你真的沒做的話
You could say you were having a takoyaki party or playing UNO with them.
可以說你們當時是在開章魚燒派對 或是在玩UNO
If you're innocent, that is.
前提是你真的沒做的話
Look me in the eyes and answer me, Tsutsumin.
看著我的眼睛回答，堤哥
The story…
我…
is true.
確實做了
Are you serious?
真的假的？
With all four of them?
你對那四個人都出手了？
Why the hell did you do that?
你幹了什麼好事啊？
What about these texts that are painful to even read?
那互傳的那些訊息呢？ 就是這些讓人說不出口的大尺度內容
You didn't send these, right? They're easy to forge, after all.
這種訊息不是你傳的吧？ 畢竟外人想偽造多少就有多少嘛
I sent those texts.
的確是我傳的
Keep him in the car until the show's over. Someone watch him.
直播結束前都不准讓他下車 找個人看好他
-What about the four victims? -They're all over 20.
-那四位被害人呢？ -她們都滿20歲了
If they were minors, we'd be in deep trouble.
說這什麼廢話？ 是未成年的話就死定了
We'll drop them from the program, but who can we find for the emcee?
如果要取消他的演出 我們現在找得到人主持嗎？
Panther's Mukai or Oriental Radio's Fujimori…
有Panther的向井先生 或東方收音機的藤森先生…
They're shooting Brunch. They won't make it.
他們在錄《早午餐》，趕不過來啦
Um…
那個…
You're still around, Nagisa?
你還在啊？渚
The guest for today's entertainment segment…
我記得今天娛樂單元的來賓是…
It's some guy with glasses.
好像是個戴眼鏡的傢伙
Mr. Norito Yashima, right?
是八嶋智人先生吧？
He wants to promote some dull play of his. What about him?
對啦，他好像是來宣傳什麼 不起演的舞台劇，幹嘛提起他？
How about I ask him?
要不要由我去拜託他？
HOMETOWN TAX GIFTS
（故鄉稅回禮）
Come in.
請進
Excuse me.
打擾了
No problem.
你好呀
-You got me the business class seat! -That's me.
-你是幫我安排商務艙的那位！ -就是我
Thanks to you, the overseas shoot was a huge hit,
多虧有你幫我們拍的國外外景 評價非常高喔
and the ratings were amazing.
而且收視率很好
I got to fly business class there and back, after all.
因為你往返都讓我坐商務艙啊
Not that I'd cut corners if I were in economy,
但我就算坐經濟艙 工作上也不會偷工減料喔
but it boosts your confidence, that's for sure.
不過對我的自信還是有加分作用
It really improved my voice, having those business class seats.
連聲量都變大了呢 想到我八嶋竟然能坐商務艙就想大喊
-About today… -Oh, right.
-今天啊… -哦，對了
Today, I'm here to promote my theater performance.
我今天是來宣傳我們劇團的公演啦
Actually, I have a big favor to ask you.
其實呢，不好意思 今天特別有事情要麻煩你
What is it, Ms. Business?
怎麼了？商務艙小姐
The thing is, our emcee…
其實主持人他…
Ken Tsutsumi? What happened to him? Covid?
堤家的阿健？他怎麼了？ 確診新冠肺炎了？
Not quite, but we need someone to fill in for him.
沒有啦，不過我們要趕快找人代替他
Shall I?
要我來嗎？
Sure. I'll do it.
可以啊，我願意做
You got me those business class seats.
畢竟你都替我訂商務艙了嘛
Just let me promote my play, and we're good.
只要節目讓我宣傳我就答應
Thank you so much.
那就麻煩你囉
No problem!
沒問題喔！
-Excuse me. -Uh-huh!
-打擾了 -不會啦！
You won't be the guest…
要請你做的不是來賓…
You want me to emcee, right?
我負責主持是吧？
I've got it covered. It's what I do best.
本人八嶋可是最擅長撐場面的男人
-What? -He said yes?
-你說什麼？ -他說願意做？
Yes.
對
He quickly agreed while browsing gifts for hometown tax donations.
他看著故鄉稅的回禮 二話不說就答應我了
I didn't know you two were close.
你們兩個感情原來那麼好啊？
We're not. It was only my second time meeting him.
不，交情不深，這是我們第二次見面
I upgraded his flight to business class for an overseas shoot the other day.
上次他要飛去國外出外景 我曾幫他升級成商務艙
And it seems he really feels indebted to me.
他好像非常感懷在心
So he wants to return the favor, huh?
所以是八嶋的報恩啊？
That sounds promising. Thanks, Nagisa.
看來能有所期待囉 這可幫了我們大忙啊，渚
You didn't have to tag along.
你其實可以不用跟來啊
I have a crucial mission to investigate the culture and customs of Showa
我自己也有以女性主義的觀點 驗證昭和時代的文化風俗
from a feminist standpoint.
這項重責大任要做
-Good morning.
-早安
There's Zucchi! Fukusuke Suzuki.
阿木出現了！他就是鈴木福助
He may not look it, but he comes from a line of gynecologists.
你別看他那副樣子 他們家代代都是婦產科醫生
I don't remember him.
我不記得他耶
Was he really around in Showa 61?
昭和61年有那號人物嗎？
Well, his shows are for adults.
畢竟他上的節目都是給成人看的
In the west, Takajin, in the east, Zucchi.
人稱“西邊的隆仁、東邊的阿木”
Hey, Zucchi! I'm a big fan of your show.
嗨，阿木先生 我一直都有看你的節目
-Thank you, Teruyo! -Subway comedy.
-謝啦，照代！ -地下鐵漫才
Hey, miss.
這位小妞
Getting enough hanky-panky?
那檔子事有做夠嗎？
What?
你說什麼？
Let's go!
我們走吧！
He just groped my butt.
他剛才摸了我的屁股
That's Zucchi for you.
那就是阿木風格啊
What does that mean? Huh?
你指的是哪門子的風格？什麼東西？
This is unbelievable!
不敢相信！
I'll sue you!
我要提告！
Can I sue him? This is outrageous!
我可以告他嗎？ 居然會有這種荒謬的事！
Seriously?
搞什麼？
Unbelievable.
令人難以置信
Let's start with introductions.
那就請她們來做自我介紹
Here are today's participants!
歡迎今天的挑戰者們！
-We're the porn star team!
-我們是成人片女演員隊！
-All right! -What?
-真棒！ -什麼？
Next up is…
接下來是…
-We're the Shinjuku Nichome drag team!
-我們是新宿二丁目男大姐隊！
And lastly…
最後是…
-We're the peppy high school girl team!
-我們是朝氣蓬勃的現任女高中生隊
-Cute!
-好可愛！ -可愛極了！
After seeing the other teams, Junko seems decent.
照這順序看下來 純子反而看起來算正常的
I'm recalling that Showa-era TV shows were like this.
昭和時代的電視節目 的確是這種風格呢
And the main emcee
讓我們來歡迎主持人
is our very own Dr. Zucchi!
就是我們的阿木醫生！
Time to make my rounds!
巡診時間到了！
Is he drinking alcohol?
他竟然邊喝酒邊主持？
Here's Mr. Norito Yashima.
八嶋智人先生入場了
Hey, this is Yashima!
大家好，我是八嶋！
I was unexpectedly chosen as the emcee for PS.
這次我臨時被提拔為《優六》主持人
I'll give it my all. I'll do my best!
我會好好加油，叔叔我會努力的！
Please don't.
請不要努力
What?
你說什麼？
Whatever you do, don't try to make a lasting impression.
請別誤以為能透過這次留下什麼成果
Just emcee with efficiency and smoothness.
你需要做的是 圓滑且順利地完成這次的主持
Who is this?
這是誰啊？
It's rude not to show your face!
太沒禮貌了，好歹露個臉吧！
I'm Kurita, the producer and general director of this program.
我是本節目的製作人兼總導播的栗田
I realize this is sudden, but we're on the brink of cancellation.
雖然事出突然 但節目正處於生死存亡的危機時刻
Following this live broadcast, a scandal involving the main emcee will go public.
現場直播結束後 我們主持人的醜聞將被公諸於世
He was sexually harassing the assistant emcees.
他對節目助理做出了騷擾行為
Whether this show will be canceled or continued, depends on you, Mr. Yashima.
本節目會就此中止還是繼續拍下去 全都要看八嶋先生你的表現
Why?
為什麼？
You must act as if you've been the emcee not only last week and the week before,
希望你能泰然自若地 裝出上週和兩週前
That's a hard ask.
簡直難如登天
If you can avoid becoming online news, that's a win for you.
只要不被寫成網路新聞 那就代表是八嶋先生獲勝
I'm so sorry. I know you only wanted to promote your play.
十分抱歉，你明明只是來宣傳而已
Can you do this for us?
你能幫幫我們嗎？
Interesting. Let's do this.
感覺很有意思，那就來吧
Are you sure you can do this?
你有信心嗎？
Of course!
那是當然的！
In this competitive entertainment industry,
在這個群雄割據的演藝圈
how did I achieve my current status?
你們以為本人八嶋 是如何獲得如今的地位的？
Do you know? Do you guys know?
你知道嗎？你們知道嗎？
You don't know? Then, let me tell you!
不知道啊？那就讓我告訴你們！
I nonchalantly slipped in.
我就只是若無其事地潛進來
I'm the guy who seems like he's been on TV for ages!
那個感覺從以前 就一直有上電視的人！
That's me, Norito Yashima!
正是我八嶋智人！
I didn't realize.
是我有眼不識泰山
I nonchalantly slipped into a historical drama and a kabuki play.
我曾在不知不覺中出演大河劇
-He's annoying. -Mr. Nonchalance!
-他話有夠多 -若無其事先生！
That's me, Norito Yashima!
就是指我，八嶋智人！
That's enough.
已經夠囉
From year one, I held a midlevel position, lacking freshness but exuding stability.
我從第一年開始就是中堅 沒有青澀時期，但很有安定感
-He's letting off steam at work. -Smoothness and efficiency are my forte!
-看來他是用工作發洩壓力的類型 -我最擅長讓事情圓滑順利地結束！
Are you done?
你滿意了嗎？
Yes.
滿意了
I'll give you a rundown of the program.
那我就跟你說明一下節目流程
No need!
不需要！
I've been the emcee for over a year now.
畢竟我從一年前就開始主持了
He's cool!
太帥了！
I'll give you a rundown of the program.
我來跟各位說明節目流程
The opening will go as usual.
開場跟往常一樣
Zucchi will crawl out from under a girl's skirt.
阿木先生會從女孩的裙底登場
-Boom! Applause, please! -What?
-登登！請拍手！ -什麼？
Next!
-什麼東西？ -接下來！
Who's up for some hanky-panky if their BWH is guessed right?
有三圍被猜中就會做那檔子事的單元
Raise your hand!
自願的人請舉手！
Me!
我！
Junko, you idiot! What are you thinking?
純子，你這個笨蛋！在想什麼啊？
Mister, stay quiet, please.
來參觀的這位先生，請你安靜
Sorry.
抱歉
After that, we'll welcome the Bulge Troop and Nip Slip Club.
接下來是一大包青年隊 以及露點女孩俱樂部會一起來參加的
-For a sumo wedgie tournament! -I can't take it anymore.
-“做那檔子事勒緊緊相撲淘汰賽” -我受不了了
Cut the crap already!
給我適可而止！
Right back at you!
你才是呢！
If you'll cause a scene, leave.
再吵的話就回去
As if you usually don't watch more explicit stuff.
什麼嘛，你平常看的東西 明明比這更色
Touché. Damn it.
無法反駁，可惡
Twenty seconds till we're live!
正式開拍前二十秒！
There you go.
麻煩你了
Thanks.
謝囉
While we're live, instructions will be given to the floor director Ujiie.
節目正式開始後的指示 將透過現場導播氏家的耳麥下達
Fifteen seconds till we're live!
開拍前十五秒！
Mr. Yashima, you don't have to be funny. Just keep it clean.
八嶋先生，你不用搞笑沒關係 總之形象要潔白無瑕
Online news can twist things out of context,
網上那些斷章取義的新聞都十分惡劣
No need to tell me.
那種事不用你說啦
I'm the guy who'll make everything fall into place.
我這男人最終總會想辦法解決問題
Three, two, one.
三、二、一
TSUTSUMIN'S PREMIUM SATURDAY
（《堤哥的優質星期六》）
Welcome to this week's PS.
歡迎收看本週的《優六》
I'm your emcee. My favorite hot pot is Akita's Kiritanpo.
主持人是火鍋只吃秋田米棒火鍋
I'm Norito Yashima aka Yashiman!
綽號“嶋哥”的八嶋智人 然後這位是…
I'm your handsome weather anchor, Jin Toriumi.
我是帥哥氣象預報員的鳥海仁
And here are the PS girls!
接下來是我們的《優六》女孩們！
-Hi, everyone!
-請多多指教！
So cute!
真是可愛呀！
Some of them couldn't join us today.
今天缺席的人有點多耶
Maybe they're tied up with end-of-term exams.
應該是因為有期末考或其他原因吧
Today, our focus is on hot pots and Valentine's Day.
那我們今天的特輯 是關於火鍋和情人節
Will you ladies give chocolates to your friends?
所以各位女生會送友情巧克力嗎？
Or to a special someone?
還是會送給特定對象呢？
-We're going to exchange chocolates. -He's so smooth.
-我們會彼此交換巧克力 -他得心應手耶
-It's like he's been the emcee every week. -Sounds nice!
-彷彿每週都是由他主持 -未免也太棒了！
As usual, get ready for helpful life tips, weekend fun ideas,
這週也一如往常 從值得一聽的生活情報
Let's dive right into the video for "What's on the menu?"
那麼今天的各主題將透過影片介紹喔
-PS!
《優六》！
WHAT'S ON THE MENU?
（今日內容是？）
We're playing the video!
開始放影片了！
PLEASE GIVE AN APOLOGY AFTER THE VIDEO
（請你在影片播完後道歉）
Your delivery is too lighthearted.
八嶋先生，你主持起來態度不夠莊重
This is an information program meant to convey bland information.
這基本上就是毫無特色 只是平淡播放資訊的情報節目
Avoid saying "yay" and keep away from giving flashy, partygoer vibes.
請避免用“耶”那種語氣炒熱氣氛 會顯得像是派對咖般輕浮
I was not giving partygoer vibes!
你竟形容成是派對咖 說得太過頭了吧！
Your face is on camera, so put on a smile.
角落視窗有照到你，請保持微笑
Right.
好
The gossip goes public in two hours, so keep it low-key.
兩個小時後會爆出醜聞 請你盡可能低調
If you understand, raise your left hand.
聽懂的話，請舉左手
Roger Dodger.
你當自己是牙醫啊？
By the way, the way you said
順便提醒你一下
"So cute!" can be seen as sexual harassment.
你剛才講“真是可愛呀！”的語氣 已經構成性騷擾了
-No way! -Don't stretch it out. Keep it crisp.
-別鬧了… -請你不要拉長語氣，口齒清晰地說
Stick to simply saying, "Cute!"
“真可愛”，請你留意
Asking if they have someone special to give chocolates to is
還有你問女生 會不會給特定的人巧克力
sexual harassment for prying into their relationship status.
等於想問出對方有沒有戀人 也算是性騷擾的一種
What else?
還有什麼來著？
You made a suggestive joke from the start, mentioning Kiritanpo.
拜託不要突然開黃腔 說“米棒”什麼的
It was not suggestive! Apologize to the people of Akita!
那才不是開黃腔咧！ 你才應該跟秋田人道歉！
This isn't broadcast in Akita.
這個節目秋田沒有播
You also made disrespectful remarks.
然後你好像還指責了什麼
Something about people not making it due to tests.
說什麼很多人缺席，有考試之類的話 就好像發生了什麼一樣
Please don't. It will get taken out of context.
停下，不然之後會被剪下來
The four seats at the front are empty, it would've been odd not to address them.
第一排空了四個位子耶！ 我不提才不自然吧
Props team, place plushies on the empty seats!
道具組，幫我放一排玩偶上去！
Despite all that I said…
雖然我說了很多，但是八嶋先生…
What is it?
幹嘛啦？
There's no uproar on social media at all.
你完全沒在社群媒體上引起騷動
That makes me feel conflicted.
那樣倒是讓我心情五味雜陳
"Oh, it's Yashima."
“是八嶋耶”
"It's Yashima today."
“今天是八嶋”
"Is it Yajima or Yashima?" That's it.
“是Yajima還是Yashima？” 就只有這些留言
No need to read them to me! And it's Yashima.
不用特地唸出來！ 然後“八嶋”是念作“Yashima”啦
I'm Inushima as well.
我也叫“Inushima”
And one more thing.
還有一件事
Yashiman sounds lewd when you say it, so don't use that name.
“嶋哥”這個詞從你的嘴裡說出來 聽起來總覺得下流，不要再說了
That's prejudice!
你這是偏見！
Tsutsumin is lewder, which is why I'm here.
就是因為堤哥更下流 節目才會走到這步田地吧
You've got 30 seconds after the video to apologize
再過三十秒影片就會播完
An inappropriate remark was made.
方才出現一些極度不妥的發言
I sincerely apologize.
在此向大家道歉
Moving on to the hot pot segment, who's taking the lead on this?
現在要進入大家引頸期盼的火鍋特輯 是由誰負責調查的呢？
Me! I, Kanon, went to investigate.
我！是由我花音去調查的
Cute!
真可愛
Kanon, you got a haircut. The very short hair looks good on you.
話說花音，你剪了頭髮呢 超短髮很適合你喔
So where did you go?
所以你去了哪裡呢？
Namegata City in Ibaraki.
茨城縣行方市
Namegata, it's a good place down there.
行方啊，那裡是個好地方呢
Let's check out the hot pots after the commercial break.
會有什麼樣的火鍋登場呢？ 將會在廣告後揭曉喔
After working overtime…
加班的日子…
The commercial break is on now!
進廣告了
GIVE AN APOLOGY AFTER THE COMMERCIAL
（請你在影片播完後道歉）
What for?
為什麼啊？
Saying "You got a haircut" can be seen as sexual harassment.
你知道問人是否剪了髮是性騷擾吧？
I had to say it.
我當然會問啊
She had long hair in the video clip.
她在影片中還是長頭髮
Now she has a buzz cut!
現在卻剃了個大平頭耶！
I had to address it!
不提就無法主持下去啊！
Did you do it for a fresh start?
是怎樣？為了淨身？ 發生了什麼事嗎？
One more thing.
另外啊
Namegata somehow comes across as lewd when you say it,
“行方”從八嶋先生嘴裡說出來 會讓人忍不住聯想到下流的事
so try not to say it.
請盡量不要講
It's just the name of a place.
不就是地名嘛
You purposely said "down there" too.
“行方那裡”是“想舔那裡”的諧音 是故意的吧
I did not!
我沒講過那句啦！
Social media is starting to buzz now.
社群媒體那邊差不多開始不安分了
The emcee has changed, after all.
一定會啊，主持人都換了
Apologize before you start getting bashed.
請在被網友抨擊前向觀眾道歉
You're the only one we can count on.
八嶋先生是我們唯一的依靠
Fine.
知道了
I'll make everything work out in the end.
最終我會想辦法解決的
Give me that.
借我一下
Go.
退下吧
I am now one of you. Give me instructions directly.
這樣我也是你們的一員了 請直接對我下達指示
Let's get through this together,
讓我們一同奮鬥吧
until 4 p.m.
到下午四點為止
Let me promote my play properly, though.
一定要好好讓我宣傳我的舞台劇喔
We're coming back in five seconds!
五秒後廣告會結束喔！
Three!
三！
Mommy is having hanky-panky…
媽媽在做那檔子事
Junko is right.
純子說得對
I'm a huge fan of porn.
我是極度好色男
I've been following the three porn stars since their debut.
成人片女演員隊的那三人 我從出道作品就很支持她們
And the team captain, Ruru Aida, played the teacher in F*ck to the Teacher!
尤其是隊長的愛田露露小姐 不就是《上到老師》裡的老師嗎？
I just realized that now!
我現在才注意到！
And I love this show so much I record it at normal speed, not at triple speed.
我超愛這節目，喜歡到不會用三倍速 而是每集都用正常速度錄下來
But today…
然而今天…
What happens if your BWH is guessed correctly?
如果三圍被正確猜中就會怎樣？
-Hanky-panky!
做那檔子事！
I'm more outraged than entertained, spoiling the fun.
心裡“不像話”的心情壓過“喜歡” 而無法享受節目
Let's start with Ruru Aida!
從愛田露露開始！
Miss High-strung next to me seems lost in thought.
隔壁的冷漠女一副心不在焉的樣子
Kiyoshi made best friends with my ex-husband.
阿清和我的前夫變成了摯友
I'm worried. But the only thing I can do is to watch.
我好擔心啊，但我也只能守望他們
If I get too involved, I'll create a time paradox.
如果涉入太深，就會發生時間悖論
What's the matter with Mrs. Compliance?
規範大嬸到底怎麼了？
Has her long stay in Showa messed with her morals?
是因為住在昭和時代太久了 道德觀終於崩壞了嗎？
That means my few days in the future
也就是說，我也因為在未來住了幾天
might have instilled compliance or something in me.
得合乎規範的觀念在我心中萌芽了？
Here goes Ruru Aida's BWH. From the top…
愛田露露的三圍從上面依序是…
An inappropriate remark was made.
方才出現一些極度不妥的發言
Shopping by weight!
秤重量購物！
If you exceed the weight limit…
如果超過體重就得…
-Hanky-panky!
做那檔子事！
I'll make a correction and apologize.
請容我修正發言並致上誠摯的歉意
Whose bulge is it? If you can guess by touch…
這是誰的一大包？ 被人摸過猜中的話就得…
-Fanky-panky!
做色色的事！
I sincerely apologize.
真的非常抱歉
With a sumo wedgie tournament…
讓我們用勒緊緊相撲淘汰賽…
-Hanky-panky!
做那檔子事！
I feel torn.
我的心正被拉扯著
I want to see a nip slip from a porn star.
我一方面期待看到成人片女演員露點
But as a father, I'm concerned about Junko.
但另一個身為父親的我則擔心著純子
Junko Ogawa!
小川純子！
Damn it. I can't tolerate this.
可惡，果然還是不能妥協
-What will you do? -I'll pull her out and take her home.
-你要幹嘛？ -讓他們停下來，我要把純子帶回去
So you're never going to watch porn again?
那你今後絕不會再看成人片了？
That's…
那是兩碼子事吧
That's a separate matter.
不能混為一談
No, it isn't.
兩者沒有不同啊
Those girls have parents, too.
那些女孩也是有父母的
You ogle other people's daughters,
自己用下流的眼光 看待別人家的女兒就沒問題
but you can't tolerate someone else eyeing your own.
卻無法忍受自己的女兒 被暴露在他人好奇的目光中啊
I'm a man. Allow me to feel a little aroused.
我也是個男人 容忍一下我多少會有慾望的事實吧
Of course. We're animals, after all.
你這樣再正常不過了 畢竟我們是生物嘛
Feminism doesn't deny male instincts.
女性主義並沒有要否定雄性本能
Nokotta!
勝負未定！
I admire those girls.
我覺得那些女孩很了不起
You do?
了不起？
They know why they're here and how to conduct themselves.
她們非常清楚自己被叫來的理由 以及應該如何表現
They're fulfilling the roles expected of them with pride.
正在展現大眾期望的自己 自豪地完成被賦予的任務
She's right.
她說得沒錯
Junko isn't the only daughter here.
不是只有純子是女兒
Everybody is somebody's daughter.
大家都是某戶人家的女兒
Even porn stars
不管是成人片女演員
and bunny girls.
還是兔女郎
The drags from Nichome are also somebody's sons.
連二丁目的男大姐們也是某人的兒子
Or daughters now.
曾經如此，現在則是女兒身
Everyone is fighting in the same ring.
大家都一樣，在同一個賽場上奮鬥
Everybody is somebody's daughter.
大家都是某個人的女兒啊
Let's start the next bout.
進入下一場對決
On your left!
是由東邊的
Miss Delinquent Girl!
大姐頭上場！
From Tokyo's Delinquent Stable.
-她出身於東京，來自大姐頭道場 -我絕對會贏
Go! You've got this, Junko!
加油！使勁上啊，純子！
#PS #YASHIMA_THE_GOAT
（#八嶋無雙）
-We're coming back in five seconds! -Amazing.
-五秒後廣告結束！ -好厲害
-Three, two… -#Yashima_The_Goat is trending.
-三、二… -“八嶋無雙”變成熱門標籤了
It's three o'clock.
現在是下午三點
Up next, we've got the weather report.
接下來是天氣報導
Toriumi!
鳥海！
Right.
是
Today, we have a low-pressure system…
今天低氣壓增強後…
Huh?
搞什麼？
Is he crying?
他是在哭嗎？
Approaching the Kyushu area.
正逐漸接近九州地區
After the weather segment, please start with an apology.
天氣報導結束後 由八嶋先生的道歉開場
What now? What did I say that was inappropriate?
這次怎麼了？哪個部分又不恰當了？
Everything! You keep making inappropriate remarks.
全部！你只要一開口 講出的話都極度不妥
First, you said, "It's all gooey inside."
首先你說了“裡面很濃稠”
What else was I supposed to say when eating a crab cream croquette?
吃蟹肉奶油可樂餅時一定會說啊
You also said the noodles were firm!
你還說了麵“很硬有嚼勁”！
I had Inaniwa udon noodles. What would you have said?
吃稻庭烏龍麵的時候一定會說的啊 那你告訴我什麼才是正確說法啊
And also…
然後就是…
Mr. Kurita, you're being overly sensitive!
栗田先生，你太敏感了啦
At this rate, he won't be able to say anything!
這樣下去八嶋先生什麼都不能說了啊
Yeah, I'm beginning to lose track.
我明白，我自己也越來越搞不清楚了
But once I started noticing, everything started to bother me!
但一在意起來，全都覺得不對勁
Hey, Camera 4!
喂，四號攝影機！
Don't pan from a girl's legs to her face!
禁止你再用這種搖鏡手法 順著從女孩們的腳拍到臉
Focus on her legs or her face, and keep the camera still!
拍腳就拍腳，拍臉就拍臉 不要亂動鏡頭，煩死了！
What is it?
怎麼了？
We've been played.
我們被耍了
The digital version is already out.
電子版已經出了
Weren't they going to hold off until the live broadcast ended?
對方不是說 會等直播節目結束後才出嗎？
They bumped it up by an hour and even upped the count to six!
他們擅自提早了一小時，而且你看
What?
不會吧！
Six affairs?
腳踏六條船？
That's Kanon. She's only 17.
那是花音，她只有17歲
She's still a minor.
還是未成年啊
We're done for!
我們完啦！
Not only that,
而且那傢伙
he even went for a guy.
連男的都不放過
RENDEZVOUS WITH WEATHER ANCHOR
（與帥哥氣象預報員幽會）
When heading out,
各位出門的時候
take your folding…
請記得攜帶折疊…
That's why he started crying.
所以他才會哭啊
Your folding…
折疊…
Folding umbrella…
折疊傘…
I was having a lapse.
我的腦袋剛才停止運轉了
Keep Kanon and Toriumi off-screen.
不要拍花音跟鳥海
-Cut to commercial now! -Okay.
-進廣告！ -是
-Nagisa, go check on the parking lot!
-渚，你去停車場看一下！ -好的！
Mr. Yashima!
八嶋先生！
I heard everything.
我全都聽到了
We can't use the video of Kamakura for the second half because Kanon's in it.
後半段鎌倉外景的影片因為有花音 我們無法播放
We're all high and dry.
我走投無路了
You're all we have, Mr. Yashima.
八嶋先生是我們最後的救命稻草
It's Yashima Hour.
這段時間就請你充分發揮
Then, I'll spend an hour promoting my play.
那我就用這一小時 好好宣傳我的舞台劇
You can't do that.
請不要那麼做
You'll have a generous 30 seconds to promote your play.
我們會在結束前三十秒讓你充分宣傳
You've got a full hour of nothing, but I'm only given 30 seconds?
明明有一小時不知道要播什麼 卻只給我三十秒？
That's absolutely ridiculous.
怎麼會有這麼荒唐的事啊
Over here.
放這裡…
Wait. Did I mention I'm good at kendama? Did my Wikipedia article say that?
奇怪，我有說過特技是劍玉嗎？ 有寫在維基百科裡嗎？
No, but Japanese people love enka ballads and kendama.
雖然沒有寫啦 但日本人最愛的就是演歌和劍玉
Am I going to do this?
要做嗎？八嶋
Up until now, I've earned a reputation for making things fall into place on set
至今為止在各種拍攝現場 人們都說只要有我在總會有辦法
and I've actually delivered.
實際上也真的都設法度過了難關
Let's do this!
那就來吧！
I can't back out of this business class seat now.
騎虎難下，商務艙也坐了
Come on, Yashima!
來吧，八嶋！
How can I not?
不上怎麼行呀？
I missed that.
我沒聽到你說了什麼
Come on!
聽一下嘛！
Social media is blowing up.
社群媒體上罵聲不斷
SIX AFFAIRS?
（腳踏六條船…）
WHAT A TURN-OFF
（讓人驚呆了）
DISAPPOINTED
（失望極了）
WHERE'S KENGO?
（健吾人呢？）
HE SHOULD APOLOGIZE!
（本人該親自出來道歉！）
Yeah!
太好啦！
I won!
我贏了！
Yes!
好耶！
That's her second win!
她淘汰兩人啦！
NAGISA
（小渚）
Hello? Hello…
喂？
-Did it connect? -No.
-有接通嗎？ -沒有
MR. OGAWA
（小川先生）
What am I doing?
我到底在做什麼啊？
Calling Mr. Ogawa won't help anything.
就算打給小川先生，他也幫不了忙啊
Hakkeyoi! Nokotta!
開始吧！勝負未定！
Nokotta!
勝負未定…
NAGISA UNABLE TO CONNECT
（小渚 無法接通）
Junko?
純子？
Huh? What happened, Junko?
怎麼了？純子發生什麼事了？
Don't touch her.
不要碰她！
Stop the camera.
攝影機不要拍了
First, let's get the menfolk out of here.
首先讓男性暫時出去一下
Cover her with a blue sheet.
然後用藍色防水布把她遮起來
-I need a female staff here. -Right.
-女性工作人員過來一下 -是
-Unzip her outfit.
-你把相撲裝的拉鍊拉開 -好
-And apply ice to the back of her head. -Right.
-用冰塊敷一下她的後腦勺 -了解
Let her recline on her back. She's got a concussion.
讓她仰躺，可能是腦震盪
Um…
那個…
We'll help you up.
我來幫你
-I'm fine. -Get up slowly.
-我沒事 -慢慢來
-Junko.
-純子
-Are you okay? -Yeah.
-你沒事吧？ -沒事
-Help her from both sides. -Right.
-你們從兩旁扶她起來 -好
Wow. What a gentleman.
真意外，他這麼紳士啊
Are you okay?
你沒事吧？
I'm sorry about the accident, mister.
抱歉讓你擔心了，伯父
Thanks.
謝謝你
How long do you plan on pumping your fists?
你要做那個勝利姿勢到什麼時候啊？
Dad, look.
老爸，你看
They gave me a hustle award.
我得了拚戰獎喔
Oh, that's cool.
是喔，這樣啊
What is it? Did something happen?
怎麼了？發生什麼事了嗎？
Junko, I need to go.
聽我說，純子，老爸要出去一下
Okay.
是喔
I left my belongings over there and…
我的東西都還放在那邊，而且…
You've fallen in love, haven't you?
你有喜歡的對象吧？
Why?
你怎麼知道？
It's obvious. How many years do you think we've lived together?
當然知道啊 你以為我們一起生活幾年了？
You've been acting strangely this whole time.
你最近一直都怪怪的
Pacing in front of the butsudan, daydreaming on the veranda,
一下在佛壇前晃來晃去 一下在陽台發呆
and you've stopped passing gas.
也不亂放屁了
That's because there's Kiyoshi and Sakae.
那是因為阿清跟紗加惠小姐都在家啊
I don't know what this person is like,
雖然我不知道對象是個怎樣的人
but with this person, you can hold hands and hug.
不過你能跟那個人牽手、擁抱
-And have rumpy-humpy, right? -Hey!
-做那檔子事對吧？ -不要亂說！
No matter how deeply you love someone, once they've passed away,
就算再怎麼喜歡
It's disrespectful to compare them.
去比較的話反而很失禮
It'd be rude to both of them.
那樣不管對哪一方都很失禮喔
Junko.
純子
I suppose
這些話不太適合 用這副模樣說出來就是了
I'll go change.
我去換衣服
Junko!
純子！
I won't be long.
我會盡早辦完事
I promise I'll return.
我一定會回來
You better. You're my dad, after all.
廢話，你可是我爸啊
Right.
說得也是
Here goes.
開始囉
I dropped it! Here we go again.
弄掉了！我馬上再來一次，開始
It's oddly entertaining.
會讓人看到出神耶，真不可思議
Let me go! Please!
請讓我進去！拜託你們！
-I have to go. -Hey!
-我一定得去！ -喂…
-Commercial! Cut to commercial! -Okay!
-廣告！快進廣告！ -好的！
I genuinely apologize to everyone for this.
各位，這次真的萬分抱歉
Get out of here! Do you want to waste all our hard work?
滾出去！
Mr. Kurita, let me offer my apology in my own words.
栗田先生，請你讓我 用自己的話跟大眾道歉
Your self-centered excuses aren't appropriate for a Saturday afternoon.
適合在星期六下午看的 不是你自以為是的辯解
It's Mr. Yashima's kendama!
而是八嶋先生的劍玉挑戰！
Nagisa!
小渚！
Mr. Ogawa!
小川先生！
I wanted to see you!
我好想見你！
That startled me!
嚇死我了！
Was it static shock?
是靜電嗎？
So?
然後呢？
Follow me.
請往這邊走
I didn't see it as sexual or power harassment.
我不認為有做出任何 性騷擾或職權騷擾的行為
I seriously intended to have an equal relationship with each of them.
我是打算對等且認真地跟每一位交往
But with six people?
但你是同時跟六個人耶
As a public figure, that's highly unpro--
身為公眾人物，你也太沒自覺了…
I'm Yashima.
我是八嶋
-That's highly unprofessional! -I never two-timed any of them.
-真的太沒有自覺了！ -交往的時期都沒有重疊
I don't believe I wronged them.
我並沒有對不起任何人
I never pressured them to see me either.
我又沒有強約他們出來
What you think doesn't matter.
你怎麼想一點都不重要
Who decides what qualifies as harassment?
誰能決定什麼舉動是騷擾？
Even if you mean well
即使你是出自好意
There is only a fine line Between love and harassment
愛情與騷擾僅一線之隔
If a girl were wearing a short skirt like this, you'd stare, wouldn't you?
比如女性穿了一件這麼短的裙子 你們都會看吧？
-No!
-不會！
-You'd totally stare! -Yes!
-會盯著看吧？ -會！
But it's not for you
但我又不是為了你
That I'm wearing a mini skirt
才穿迷你裙的
May I? Something's been bothering me this entire time.
可以問一個問題嗎？ 我一直都很在意這件事
You'd totally eye that
那這個你們會看吧？
It's unnatural not to
不看的話才顯得不自然
Mm-hmm, that's sexy
嗯哼，實在很性感
Let us entertain that thought, at least
只是在心裡想想，就放過我們吧
But it's not for you
但我又不是為了你
That I'm showing my cleavage
才露出乳溝的
That's also harassment
那樣也是騷擾
You're overly sensitive
你太敏感了！
That's harassment
早已形成騷擾
That's why TV is boring
所以電視節目才變得無趣
Who decides what qualifies as harassment?
誰能決定什麼舉動是騷擾？
Someone please establish guidelines
拜託來制定一套明確準則吧
Why not try to see them as if they were your own daughter?
大家就將對方 想成是自己的女兒如何？
-Who?
-你哪位？
Porn stars and idols
不管是成人片女演員，還是偶像
Ordinary women and old women
一般女性或是老太太
Don't say things You wouldn't say to your daughter
不會對女兒說的話就不要亂說
Don't do things You wouldn't do to your daughter
不會對女兒做的事就不要亂做
That would distress your daughter
會讓女兒傷心的事就不要去做
Do things that bring her joy
去做會讓女兒感到開心的行為
That's our guideline
那便是我們的準則
HANKY-PANKY HUSTLE AWARD
（《不早睡的夜晚會做那檔子事》 拚戰獎）
Don't be hard on your father
不要討厭你爸爸
Junko.
純子
Don't disappoint your father
別讓你爸爸失望
Don't say things You wouldn't say to your daughter
不會對女兒說的話就不要亂說
Don't be hard on your father
不要討厭你爸爸
Don't do things That would distress your daughter
會讓女兒傷心的事就不要去做
Don't disappoint your father
別讓你爸爸失望
We can't be singing.
現在不是高歌的時候啦
The commercial break is over. Thirty seconds left!
廣告已經結束了 只剩下三十秒就要開拍
It's all right.
不要緊
Mr. Yashima…
八嶋先生他…
Did you enjoy the show?
今天的節目看得盡興嗎？
Make sure to post your thoughts on X, former Twitter.
感想請用X，也就是原推特跟我們說
Now, allow me to introduce Kamuyarai,
那麼由今天的主持人
the latest play from the theater group COMECOME MINIKI-NA, of which I'm a part.
八嶋智人參與演出
It will be running from February 1st to 11th at Za-Koenji 1,
將自2月1日起至11日止 在座高圓寺第一劇場
and at the Kintetsu Art Museum on February 17th and 18th.
2月17及18日則是在近鐵美術館演出
Please come and see it.
請務必來劇場觀看喔
Now, on next week's 300th anniversary episode,
那麼下週就是第300集紀念
we're hosting a gourmet delivery championship!
我們將舉行網購美食大賽！
There's still more time?
什麼？還有時間？
Remember, everyone.
跟各位說件事喔
When flying, always opt for economy class!
飛機一定要坐經濟艙！
Nori and steam…
滿滿的海苔與熱氣…
We've cut to commercial!
進廣告了！
-That's it for today! Good work! -Good work!
-今天節目錄製完成！辛苦了！ -辛苦囉！
Good work.
辛苦了
I suppose things worked out in the end.
最後也算是撐過去了吧
I might get a first-class seat for you next time!
下次我可能會為你訂頭等艙喔！
Sure.
好耶
Nagisa.
小渚
Mr. Ogawa,
小川先生
thank you for coming.
謝謝你來找我
What's the matter?
等等，你要做什麼？
Just as I thought.
果然是這樣
Subtitle translation by: Ai Matsuoka
字幕翻譯：黃可涵
What?
怎麼回事？
Will you scan the QR code?
要顯示QR碼？要掃一下嗎？
I've been waiting ever since it was marked as read. So why?
我看到已讀之後就一直在等 這是為什麼？
You have a smartphone addiction.
你有嚴重的手機依賴症
You have second-grade syndrome!
你是得了中二病嗎？
Stupid girl.
-你這笨蛋 -秋津
Akitsu, is your mother…
-你的母親該不會是… -可惡
Are Mr. Ogawa and I not allowed to be together?
我跟小川先生不能在一起嗎？